// import $ from 'jquery';
// import 'bootstrap';
// import 'bootstrap/dist/css/bootstrap.min.css';
// import './css/styles.css';

function getElements(response) {
    // $('#question').html(response.results[0].question);

    $('#answer').html(`<h6>Answer</h6> ${response.results[0].correct_answer}`);
    
    // my Trivia game Database

    const triviaData = [{
            // for question 1
            question: `${response.results[0].question}`,
            a: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[0]}`,
            b: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[2]}`,
            c: `${response.results[0].correct_answer}`,
            d: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[1]}`,
            correct: "c"
        },
        {
            // for question 2
            question: `${response.results[0].question}`,
            a: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[2]}`,
            b: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[1]}`,
            c: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[0]}`,
            d: `${response.results[0].correct_answer}`,
            correct: "d"
        },
        {
            // for question 3
            question: `${response.results[0].question}`,
            a: `${response.results[0].correct_answer}`,
            b: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[1]}`,
            c: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[0]}`,
            d: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[2]}`,
            correct: "a"
        },
        // {
        //     // for question 4
        //     question: `${response.results[0].question}`,
        //     a: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[1]}`,
        //     b: `${response.results[0].correct_answer}`,
        //     b: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[2]}`,
        //     d: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[0]}`,

        //     correct: "b"
        // },
        // {
        //     // for question 5
        //     question: `${response.results[0].question}`,
        //     a: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[1]}`,
        //     b: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[2]}`,
        //     c: `${response.results[0].correct_answer}`,
        //     d: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[0]}`,

        //     correct: "c"
        // },
        // {
        //     // for question 6
        //     question: `${response.results[0].question}`,
        //     a: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[1]}`,
        //     b: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[2]}`,
        //     c: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[0]}`,
        //     d: `${response.results[0].correct_answer}`,
        //     correct: "d"
        // },
        // {
        //     // for question 7
        //     question: `${response.results[0].question}`,
        //     a: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[1]}`,
        //     b: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[2]}`,
        //     c: `${response.results[0].correct_answer}`,
        //     d: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[0]}`,
        //     correct: "c"
        // },
        // {
        //     // for question 8
        //     question: `${response.results[0].question}`,
        //     a: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[1]}`,
        //     d: `${response.results[0].correct_answer}`,
        //     c: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[0]}`,
        //     d: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[2]}`,
        //     correct: "b"
        // },
        // {
        //     // for question 9
        //     question: `${response.results[0].question}`,
        //     a: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[1]}`,
        //     b: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[2]}`,
        //     c: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[0]}`,
        //     d: `${response.results[0].correct_answer}`,
        //     correct: "d"
        // },
        // {
        //     // for question 10
        //     question: `${response.results[0].question}`,
        //     a: `${response.results[0].correct_answer}`,
        //     b: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[1]}`,
        //     c: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[2]}`,
        //     d: `${response.results[0].incorrect_answers[0]}`,
        //     correct: "a"
        // },
        // {
        //     // for question 11
        //     question: `${response.results[10].question}`,
        //     a: `${response.results[10].incorrect_answers[1]}`,
        //     b: `${response.results[10].incorrect_answers[2]}`,
        //     c: `${response.results[10].incorrect_answers[0]}`,
        //     d: `${response.results[10].correct_answer}`,
        //     correct: "d"
        // },
        // {
        //     // for question 12
        //     question: `${response.results[11].question}`,
        //     a: `${response.results[11].incorrect_answers[1]}`,
        //     b: `${response.results[11].correct_answer}`,
        //     c: `${response.results[11].incorrect_answers[0]}`,
        //     d: `${response.results[11].incorrect_answers[2]}`,
        //     correct: "b"
        // },
        // {
        //     // for question 13
        //     question: `${response.results[12].question}`,
        //     a: `${response.results[12].incorrect_answers[1]}`,
        //     b: `${response.results[12].correct_answer}`,
        //     c: `${response.results[12].incorrect_answers[0]}`,
        //     d: `${response.results[12].incorrect_answers[2]}`,
        //     correct: "b"
        // },
        // {
        //     // for question 14
        //     question: `${response.results[13].question}`,
        //     a: `${response.results[13].incorrect_answers[1]}`,
        //     b: `${response.results[13].incorrect_answers[0]}`,
        //     c: `${response.results[13].incorrect_answers[2]}`,
        //     d: `${response.results[13].correct_answer}`,
        //     correct: "d"
        // },
        // {
        //     // for question 15
        //     question: `${response.results[14].question}`,
        //     d: `${response.results[14].correct_answer}`,
        //     a: `${response.results[14].incorrect_answers[1]}`,
        //     b: `${response.results[14].incorrect_answers[0]}`,
        //     c: `${response.results[14].incorrect_answers[2]}`,
        //     correct: "a"
        // }
    ];
    response


    const triviaBoard = $("#board");
    // querySelectorAll would help me get all elements with the answer class abd store them as an array so I can loop through them later
    const allAnswers = document.querySelectorAll(".answer");
    const allQuestions = $("#question");
    const a_text = $("#a_text");
    const b_text = $("#b_text");
    const c_text = $("#c_text");
    const d_text = $("#d_text");
    const submitBtn = $("#submit");

    let currentTriviaQuestion = 0;
    let score = 0;

    loadTrivia();

    // writing the function to load each of my trivia questions

    function loadTrivia() {
        deselectAnswers();

        const currentTriviaData = triviaData[currentTriviaQuestion];

        allQuestions.text(currentTriviaData.question);
        a_text.text(currentTriviaData.a);
        b_text.text(currentTriviaData.b);
        c_text.text(currentTriviaData.c);
        d_text.text(currentTriviaData.d);

    }

    function deselectAnswers() {
        // looping through each answer class stored in the allAnswers variable
        allAnswers.forEach(answer => answer.checked = false);
    }

    // function deselectAnswers() {
    //     // Convert NodeList to an array
    //     const answersArray = Array.from(allAnswers);

    //     // Loop through each answer in the array and set checked to false
    //     answersArray.forEach(answer => answer.checked = false);
    // }

    function getSelected() {
        let newanswer;

        allAnswers.forEach(answer => {
            // the .checked will only work for checkboxes and radio buttons and its used to determine which one was checked(clicked) out of the remaining
            if (answer.checked) {
                newanswer = answer.id
            }

        });
        // returning the newanswer after determining that particular answer based on its id
        return newanswer;
    }

    submitBtn.click(function () {
        const selectedanswer = getSelected();

        if (selectedanswer) {
            // if the answer checked by my user is same as the answer stored in the (correct )key in the triviaData array, increase my user's score


            console.log(triviaData[currentTriviaQuestion]);
            if (selectedanswer === triviaData[currentTriviaQuestion].correct) {
                score++;
            }
            currentTriviaQuestion++;

            if (currentTriviaQuestion < triviaData.length) {
                loadTrivia();
            } else {
                triviaBoard.html(`
                <h2>You answered ${score}/${triviaData.length} questions correctly</h2> 
                ${getCurrentTime()}
                
            `);
            }

        }
        localStorage.setItem(triviaBoard, JSON.stringify(triviaBoard));
    })

};




function getCurrentTime() {
    let now = new Date();
    let hours = now.getHours();
    let minutes = 0;
    if (now.getMinutes() + 1 < 10) {
        minutes = '0' + now.getMinutes().toString();
    } else {
        minutes = now.getMinutes();
    }
    let period;
    if (hours >= 12) {
        period = 'PM';
    } else {
        period = 'AM';
    }
    let date = `${now.getMonth() + 1}/${now.getDate()}/${now.getFullYear()}`;
    let time;
    if (hours > 12) {
        time = `${hours - 12}:${minutes} ${period}`;
    } else if (hours == 0) {
        time = `${hours + 12}:${minutes} ${period}`;
    } else {
        time = `${hours}:${minutes} ${period}`;
    }
    return `${date} ${time}`;
};






function displayCategories() {
    let request = new XMLHttpRequest();
    const url = "https://opentdb.com/api_category.php"

    request.onreadystatechange = function () {
        if (this.readyState === 4 && this.status === 200) {
            const response = JSON.parse(this.responseText);
            let html = '';
            for (let i = 0; i < response.trivia_categories.length; i++) {
                html = '';
                html += `<option value="${response.trivia_categories[i].id}">`;
                html += `${response.trivia_categories[i].name}`;
                html += `</option>`;
                $('#trivia-questions').append(html);
            }
        }
    }
    request.open("GET", url, true);
    request.send();
}

function getQuestion(categoryId) {
    $('#answer').hide();
    let request = new XMLHttpRequest();
    const url = `https://opentdb.com/api.php?amount=1&category=${categoryId}`
    request.onreadystatechange = function () {
        if (this.readyState === 4 && this.status === 200) {
            const response = JSON.parse(this.responseText);
            getElements(response);
        }
    }
    request.open("GET", url, true);
    request.send();
}


$(document).ready(function () {
    let categoryId = 9;
    getQuestion(categoryId);
    displayCategories();


    $("#next").click(function () {
        $("#second-form").show();
        $("#first-form").hide();
    });

    $('#next-button').click(function () {
        getQuestion(categoryId);
        $('#answer').hide();
        $('#info_div').show();
       
    });

    $('#answer-button').click(function () {
        $('#info_div').hide();
        $('#answer_div').show();
        $('#answer').show();
    });

    // $("#submit").click(function () {
    //     $("#board").show();
    //     $(".triviaQuestions").hide();
    // });

    $('#trivia-questions').change(function () {
        //console.log($('#trivia-questions option:selected').val());
        categoryId = $('#trivia-questions option:selected').val();
        getQuestion(categoryId);
    });


});


//http://jservice.io/api/random
//https://opentdb.com/api.php?amount=1&category=17